Finding Aid for Neil Staebler papers, 1944-1992
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Political Files, 1950-1975
  - Democratic National Committee, 1950-circa 1968
    - Subcommittee on Party Organization (Box 185)
    - National Committeeman (Box 186)
    - National Committeewoman (Box 186)
    - National Chairman (Box 186)
    - Operation Support (Box 187)
    - National Committee meetings (Box 187)
    - National Field Training Course (Box 187)
    - Topical files: [A-N] (Box 188)
    - Topical files: [N-S] (Box 189)
    - Topical files: [S-Z] (Box 190)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 190)
    - Miscellaneous and unprocessed (Box 311)
    - Miscellaneous and unprocessed (Box 312)
  - Michigan governors/senators files, 1952-circa 1968
    - Governor G. Mennen Williams
      - Schedule correspondence, 1952-1960 (Box 191)
      - Message correspondence, 1954-1959 (Box 191)
      - Weekly column papers (Box 191)
      - Radio program miscellanea (Box 191)
      - Governor's Office correspondence (Box 191)
      - Miscellaneous, 1952-1960 (Box 191)
      - Presidential campaign, 1956 (Box 191)
      - Testimonial dinners, 1952-1960 (Box 191)
      - Inaugurals, 1951-1959 (Box 192)
      - Conferences (Box 192)
      - Party strategy and accomplishments (Box 192)
      - Topical files (Box 193)
    - Governor John B. Swainson (Box 193)
    - Senator Blair Moody (Box 194)
    - Senator Blair Moody (Box 195)
    - Senator Patrick McNamara (Box 195)
    - Senator Philip A. Hart (Box 196)
  - Calendar-Invitation file, 1951-1975
    - Agenda-diary, 1951-1957 (Box 197)
    - Agenda-diary, 1958-1960 (Box 198)
    - Appointment books, 1958-1963; 7 volumes (Box 198)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 199)
      (5x7 index cards)
    - April-July 1964 (Box 200)
    - August-December 1964 (Box 201)
    - (lacking August 1965), 1965-February 1966 (Box 202)
    - March 1966-June 1967 (Box 203)
    - July 1967-1968 (Box 204)
    - 1969-September 1970 (Box 205)
    - October 1970-July 1975 (Box 206)
      (no August 1973-October 1974)
  - Federal Agencies and Departments
    (also in box 311)
    - [A-I] (Box 207)
    - [J-P] (Box 208)
    - [P-Z] (Box 209)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Democratic Club (later committee) of Washtenaw County Records, 1948-1951 (Box 210)
    - Democratic Club of Washtenaw County (Box 211)
    - Democratic Club of Washtenaw County (cont.)
      - County conventions, 1948-1950 (Box 212)
      - Dawson for Congress campaign, 1950 (Box 212)
      - Card files, 2 boxes (Box 212)
    - Michigan Democratic Clubs, 1951-1969 (Box 213)
    - State government, 1950-1960
      (include correspondence, press releases, etc)
      - State officers (Box 214)
      - State agencies: [A-C] (Box 214)
      - State agencies: [D-Z] (Box 215)
      - Sampling of press releases and correspondence concerning political appointments (Box 216)
      - State government offices (Box 217)
      - Out-of-state correspondence [A-W], 1952-1972 (Box 218)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 219)
    - Sound tapes (Box 220)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 221)
    - Unprocessed (Box 221)
    - Democratic Party County Files (Box 313)
    - Democratic Party Congressmen Files (Box 313)
    - Democratic Party Congressmen Files (Box 314)
    - Democratic Party Policy (Box 314)
    - Non-Michigan state and foreign political parties (Box 319)
- Federal Election Commission, 1975-1978
  Staebler's membership on the U.S. Federal Election Commission, 1975-1978, is documented in the next series.
  - Advisory Opinion Requests and related
    - 1975
      - Index (Box 222)
      - Requests, 1-23 (Box 222)
      - Requests, 24-144 (Box 223)
      - Requests, 1-250 (correspondence) (Box 223)
      - Requests, 251-350 (correspondence) (Box 224)
      - General (Box 224)
      - Opinion of Counsel, 1-131 (Box 224)
      - Miscellaneous files (Box 224)
      - Progress report of Commission (Box 224)
    - 1976
      - Requests, 1-117 (Box 224)
      - Opinion of Counsel, 1-76 (Box 224)
      - Miscellaneous files (Box 224)
      - Opinion Requests, 1-1000 (Box 225)
    - 1977
      - Requests, 1-71 (Box 225)
    - 1978
      - Requests, 1-76 (Box 226)
      - Miscellaneous files, 1978 (Box 226)
  - Topical file, 1975-1978
    - [A-C] (Box 227)
    - [C-F] (Box 228)
    - [G-01 (Box 229)
    - [P-T] (Box 230)
    - [T-Z] (Box 231)
  - Staebler files
    - Staebler Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 231)
    - Staebler Speeches and Invitations (Box 231)
    - Staebler biography (Box 232)
    - Staebler-copies and drafts (Box 232)
    - Staebler-dissents (Box 232)
    - Staebler-personal (Box 232)
    - Staebler-Summary of accomplishments (Box 232)
    - David Vaughn files (Box 232)
    - Gingrich campaign fund (Box 232)
    - Miscellaneous files (Box 232)
  - Published and miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous files (Box 233)
    - Procedures and Reference Manual; Reports Analysis Section (Box 233)
    - Reports and Testimony (Box 234)
    - Reports and Testimony (Box 235)
    - Reports and Testimony (Box 236)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 236)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 237)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 238)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 239)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 240)
    - Miscellaneous and unprocessed (Box 306)
    - Miscellaneous and unprocessed (Box 307)
    - Miscellaneous and unprocessed (Box 308)
- Issues, 1950s-1980s
  Staebler's Issues File and concerns topics of public policy and subjects of current interest (primarily political) confronting American society since World War II. This series is comprised of two alphabetical subseries covering different periods of time (with some overlap).
  - 1950s-1970s
    - A-By (Box 241)
    - By-Cong (Box 242)
    - Cons-Di (Box 243)
    - Di-Election laws (Box 244)
    - Election laws-H (Box 245)
    - I-Issues (National) (Box 246)
    - Issues (National)-Issues (State), 1960 (Box 247)
    - Issues (State) 1961-Legislation (Box 248)
    - Legislative-Le (Box 249)
    - Li-Michigan Week (Box 250)
    - Michigan Week-Min (Box 251)
    - Min-News (Box 252)
    - News-Purchase Orders (Box 253)
    - R-Reg (Box 254)
    - Tel-Speakers (Box 255)
    - Speakers-Studies (Box 256)
    - Studies (Box 257)
    - Su-Z (Box 258)
  - 1970s-1980s
    - A-C (Box 301)
    - D-I (Box 302)
    - I-P (Box 303)
    - P-R (Box 304)
    - R-Z (Box 305)
- American Veterans Committee, 1944-1951
  - 1944-1947 (Box 259)
  - 1948-1951 (Box 260)
- Speeches and Articles, 1950-1968
  - Staebler speeches and background for speeches, 1950-1961 (Box 261)
  - Staebler speeches and background for speeches, 1962-1968 (Box 262)
  - Staebler books and articles (Box 262)
  - Appearances, seminars, articles, etc. (Box 320)
- Ann Arbor Citizens Council
  - Subject files (Box 263)
  - Subject files (Box 264)
  - Subject files (Box 265)
  - Subject files (Box 266)
  - Subject files (Box 322)
- Personal
  - Financial
    - Staebler and Son (Box 267)
    - Dixie Oil (Box 267)
    - University microfilms (Box 267)
    - Realty (Box 267)
    - Realty (Box 268)
  - Trips (Box 269)
  - Trips (Box 270)
  - Teaching (Box 270)
  - Books on politics (Box 270)
  - Unitarian Church (Box 270)
  - Family (Box 270)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 270)
  - Burnette Staebler papers (Box 271)
  - Miscellaneous and unprocessed (Box 281)
  - Miscellaneous and unprocessed (Box 282)
  - Miscellaneous and unprocessed (Box 283)
  - Miscellaneous and unprocessed (Box 321)
- Visual materials
  The Visual Materials series consists of photographs and motion picture films. The photographs are primarily of Staebler with political figures and at political events.
  - Photographs, 1957-1971; undated
    - Billboards (Box 279)
    - Oil business and miscellaneous (Box 279)
    - Political activities
      - Dated
        - 1957-1960 (Box 279)
        - 1961-1964 (Box 279)
        - 1965-1971 (Box 279)
      - Undated
        - Staebler with John Kennedy and Lyndon Johnson (Box 279)
        - Staebler with G. Mennen Williams, Philip Hart, John Swainson, and Jerome Cavanagh (Box 279)
        - Staebler with various political figures (Box 279)
        - Not Staebler (Box 279)
    - Portraits
      - Formal (Box 279)
      - Informal (Box 279)
    - Burnette Staebler and Staebler family (Box 279)
  - Films, 1963-1964; all 16mm, black & white, sound
    - Foreign aid, 4 min. negative (Box 279)
    - College loans, 4 min. negative (Box 279)
    - Defense budget, 4 min. negative (Box 279)
    - Redistricting Michigan, Tax cuts, Youth corps, negative (Box 279)
    - Committee assignments, Tax cuts, negative (Box 279)
    - Announcement, January 4, 1964; positive (Box 279)